

# **Michael Baiyeshea**

Nationality: Nigerian (Nigeria)

(+234) 7043133403

Date of birth: 09/03/1997

**Gender:** Male

**■ Email address:** baiyesheamk@gmail.com

**Skype:** live:.cid.b5432c836bd8ab1f

• Address: House 64 Poultry Road, Jahi One, Abuja, 900108 Federal Capital Teritory (Nigeria)

• Address: 42, Lobito Crescent Wuse 2, FCT, 900288 Abuja-Central Locations (Nigeria)

### **ABOUT ME**

An experienced System Software Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the program development industry (MIS, EMR, ERP...). Skilled in PHP, jQuery, Program Development, JavaScript, and C#. Strong system analyst professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Computer Science from Kogi State University (Best departmental graduating student). On personality, well, picture a phlegmatic :-). I am very open-minded, I don't give up easily, I am very determined and dedicated to whatever I set my mind to. A die-hard FIFA lover. Also a die-hard music lover(A keyboardist and a bass player), all to mention but a few. Above all, a lover of God!

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **System Analyst/Software Developer**

Mr. Patrick Ogbuitepu [ 30/03/2018 - Current ]

Address: No. 40 Balogun Estate Majek, Opposite Fara-Park Estate Lekki-Epe Expressway, Ajah, 32345 Lagos (Niger

ia) - http://www.maybeachtech.com

City: Lagos
Country: Nigeria

Email address: maybeachtech@gmail.com

Name of unit or department: Development Team - Business or sector: Information and communication

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SboESYE6jgM

- Creating and maintaining clients' websites and applications (mobile & web)
- Performing full spectrum of web-related tasks including rapid prototyping, design and layout and optimization
- Programming server side applications with PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MySQL, HTML5 and CSS
- Analyses and also effect functional requirements of clients business processes
- Holds training sessions to client upon deployment of a software

### **Asst. Lead Software Architect**

**Kenneth Uvah** [ 04/02/2018 - Current ]

Address: 42, Lobito Crescent, Wuse 2, FCT, 32345 Abuja (Nigeria) - https://hyella.com/

City: Abuja Country: Nigeria

Email address: info@hyella.com

- Business or sector: Information and communication

- Receives clients' (new and existing) requirements and implement them on the company's software (HYELLA)
- Part of the development on Telehealth, a mobile app that synchronizes with the company's software
- Makes upgrades to different business functions as new ideas come by from the development team or from our clients
- Sets up the software to meet specific new clients request. This requires me adjusting codes to suit their specific business functions

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### **Bachelor of Science**

Prince Abubakar Abdu University (Formerly Kogi State University) [ 10/01/2015 - 30/04/2019 ]

Address: PAAU, P.M.B 1008, Anyigba Kogi State, Nigeria, Anyigba (Nigeria)

https://www.ksu.edu.ng/

Field(s) of study: Mathematical Sciences (Computer Major)

Final grade: 4.31/5.00 - Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Thesis: AUTOMATION OF BILLING MANAGEMENT SYSTEM IN SMALL, MEDIUM AND LARGE SCALE ENTERPRISES

https://drive.google.com/file/d/10bAPAQ02GqEPTg7Up0AJkf60LnOfQV30/view?usp=sharing

I covered a wide significant range of **Mathematical** and **Statistical** courses in my first and second year. Then I majored into Computer courses in my final 2 years

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Yoruba (Nigeria)

Other language(s):

# **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1** 

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

#### Document/Media

Google Docs / MS Office(MS Visio, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel ) / Google Drive / Adobe Fireworks / Microsoft Word

# **Software Development**

Web: HTML, JAVA script, PHP, CSS, XML, XSL ... / Microsoft .NET Programming (CSharp) / SQL/MYSQL / MongoDB Query Language

#### **Personality**

Team-work oriented / Work Under Pressure / Team player/ Team leader / Passionate, Enthusiastic, Zealous

# **VOLUNTEERING**

# **Living Hope Foundation**

[ Abuja, Nigeria, 08/06/2020 - Current ]

I interview beneficiaries after each outreach to get reviews on their satisfaction rate and ways to improve the quality of our services.

I assist the President in drafting out activities/Order of Program for any of the Foundation's outreaches also in determining what specific palliative is most needed in specific locations

I give speeches to beneficiaries of different outreaches prior to distribution of palliatives

https://www.instagram.com/livinhopef/